诸位好
Good day.
今日 2014年7月1日
On this day, July 1st 2014...
今时 6点整
at this hour, 0600...
我们正身处这世上第一个航空发射站
we are at the very first airport in the world...
在过去7年里 这一话题饱受争议
topic of so much controversy over the past 7 years...
并且仍在继续
has continued development.
环保组织以及
Protests from environmental
一些发展中国家对其仍持反对意见
groups and a number of developing countries continue.
据声称CW7是解决全球变暖的唯一方案
It had been claimed The CW7 is the answer to global warming.
而我们就是见证者
And we are witnesses.
领导人们呼吁全球变暖问题不容小觑
Leaders who argue that global warming can no longer be ignored.
今天 79个国家将把CW7
Today, 79 countries will began dispersing CW7...
发射到外逸层
in the upper layers of the atmosphere.
人民惊喜地发现全球平均气温被降了下来
And surprisingly bring down the average global temperature...
仅一天时间
It is just a day away that...
据科学家所言
According to scientists...
人工冷却剂CW7
the artificial cooling substance CW7...
将成功地将全球均温
will succeed in bringing average
降至可控范围
global temperature down to manageable level.
对于解决全球变暖问题具有革命性的意义
As a revolutionary solution to mankind's warming of the planet.
雪国列车
车
列
雪国列车
发射CW7后的不久
整个大地陷入一片冰封
物种灭绝
那些登上诺亚方舟号列车的为数不多的人类
最后得以幸存
点人头
Head check.
17年后
公元 2031年
排好队
Alright, get in line.
都坐下
Everybody sit down.
1 2 3 4 5 6
One, two, three... four, five, six...
别停下
Keep going.
继续
Go on.
你 给我坐下
Hey you, sit down.
Curtis 坐下
Curtis, sit down.
坐下
Sit down.
我说了给我坐下
I said sit down!
- 你他妈的在干什么呢  - 数数
- What the fuck are you doing? - Counting.
你就不能坐着数 你想挨枪子吗 你疯了吗
Can't you sit and count? You want to get shot? You're crazy.
闭嘴 Edgar 我在思考问题
Shut up, . I'm thinking.
你们中有谁拉过小提琴
Are there any experienced violinist here?
手举起来
Raise your hands.
小提琴家
Violinist!
起来 上前
Stand up, come forward.
来这里取食物
Food, come and get it.
小提琴家 真可笑
Violinist, they're having a laugh.
前车厢的那些混蛋以为我们是他们的所有物
Those bastards in the front sections think they own us.
吃着牛排 听着音乐
Eating their steak dinner and listening to string quarter.
等我们冲到前面就不一样了
Will be different when we get there.
我想吃牛排
I want steak.
不好意思 长官
Excuse me, sir.
我妻子和我曾在波士顿管弦乐队演奏小提琴
My wife and I played violin in the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
我是首席小提琴手
I was first chair.
你还会弹吗
Can you still play?
当然 永远不会忘
Of course, you never forget.
伸出手来
Show me your hands.
你 跟我来
You, follow me.
行李都不用了 带着你的手就行
Leave your belongings, we just need your hands.
不是两个人
Not both?
是两只手
Yes, both hands.
我妻子Doris演奏的也很美 甚至比我还好
My wife Doris plays beautifully. Better than me, even.
他们只要一个人
They just need one person.
那我不去了
Then I won't go.
Doris Doris
Doris, Doris...
坐下 所有人
Sit down, everyone.
坐下
Sit down.
- 他们怎么能  - 坐下
- They can't just... - Sit down.
这些该死的混蛋
Those fucking bastards.
现在还未到时机
Now isn't the time.
什么时候才是时机
When is the time?
很快
Soon.
Doris
Doris.
我会回来的 Doris 没事的
I'll be back, Doris. It's alright.
我会回来的
I'll come back.
牛排吃起来什么味道来着
What does steak taste like again?
我吃过一次 但我不记得了
I had it once, but I can't remember.
如果你记不起来就不如忘了吧
If you can't remember then it's better to forget.
煎牛排的时候是什么味儿
What does it smell like when it's cooked?
一定飘香四溢
It must emanate around the place.
Curtis
Curtis.
是这个吗
It is this?
不是
It's not it.
抱歉
Sorry.
Curtis 这儿
Curtis, here!
Timbo
Timbo!
你怎么样 小家伙
How's it hanging, buddy?
击个拳
Give me a pow.
听着
Listen.
我想要你的蛋白块
I think I need that protein block.
我用这块换你的那块怎么样
How about I trade you, this one for that one?
不行
No.
真会讨价还价 Curtis
Nice bargaining power, Curtis.
把这块给我 我把这块给你
Here, give me this one, I'll give you that...
- 别急 别急  - 到这来 Timmy
- Relax, relax...  - Come here, Timmy.
坐这里
Come right...
我有个主意
I have an idea.
我把这块还有那块都换给你
I'll give you this one and that one for that one.
- 怎么样  - 不
- What do you say?  - No.
抓他回来
Go get him.
Timmy
Timmy!
Timothy 你妈妈会揍你的
Timothy, your mom is gonna give you a damn good spanking.
他去哪了
Where the fuck he went?
到这来 把那个给我
Hey, come here. Give it to me.
嗨 Jose 你还好吗
Hi Jose, how are you doing?
Timmy 快来帮忙
Timmy! Work with me here.
Edgar 你怎么让他跑上去了
Edgar, why did you let him get up there?
不是我的错 他自己上去的 他可滑头了
No I didn't, he got up there by himself. He's very nimble.
- 他才5岁  - 5岁的小滑头
- He's 5. - He's a very nimble 5 year old.
Timmy 宝贝儿快下来
Timmy, sweety come down.
到这来
Come here.
我要拿什么你才愿意换
What do you want for it?
火车上的所有东西
In the whole wide train?
In the whole wide train.
那个球
The ball.
球 不行
The ball? No.
抱歉 这个可不行 我没办法
No, I'm sorry I can't do that. I can't do that.
不行 我要那个球 整整一小时
Yes, I get the ball for a whole hour.
成交
Done.
Curtis 是时候了吗
Curtis. Is it time?
还没 Tanya 快了
Not yet, Tanya. Soon.
红纸条
Red paper?
没错 我们等的就是这个
Yeah, it's the one we've been waiting for.
线人给了我们一个名字
Our informant gave us a name.
南
N, a, m...
南宫民秀
Nam Koong Min Soo.
他是安全系统的专家 现在在监狱车厢
He's a security expert. He's in the prison section now.
你开玩笑吧 他在监狱
Wait, you're joking right? He's in prison?
出去
Out of here.
我的意思是 我们哪有机会...
I'm just saying, what kind of chance do we have...
Edgar
Edgar.
我在想如果真如这人所言
I just think if this guy
他是个牛逼的安全系统专家...
says that he's such a great security expert...
- 为什么他不能越狱呢  - 够了 出去
- why can't he just break himself? - That's enough! Go.
走吧 Tim
Let's go, Tim.
来 我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
Edgar不过是想帮忙 你知道的
Edgar just wants to help, you know.
他做的一切都是为你
He thinks the world of you.
他不该这么崇拜我
He shouldn't worship me the way he does.
我不是他想的那种人
I'm not who he thinks I am.
又有谁是呢
Few of us ever are.
我们在这
Alright, we're here.
尾厢 隔离箱 监狱厢
Tail section, quarantine section, prison section.
大门 大门 大门
Gate, gate, gate.
三扇大门同时打开的时间只有4秒
4 seconds when all three gates are open at once.
我们有4秒穿过3道门然后把南弄出来
We have 4 second to go through three gates and bust Nam out.
然后让南把剩下的门打开
That Nam gets us the rest of the way.
我们的命运就握于他手了
Our fate depends on this man.
没错
Yeah.
如果他愿意和我们合作
If we can get him to cooperate he
我们就可以一路占领到前车厢
can take us all the way to the front of the train.
最前车厢
Very front section?
是的
Yeah.
从这里直到火车最前面
From here right through the front of the train.
必须一击必胜
Everything in one stroke.
控制了引擎就控制了列车
We control the engine, we control the world.
没有引擎其他都是空谈
Without that, we have nothing.
过去所有革命
All past revolutions have
之所以失败都是因为没有夺取引擎
failed because they couldn't take the engine.
你的意思是
What are you saying?
这一次我们夺取引擎
This time we take the engine.
之后呢
Then what?
杀了他们
We kill them.
Wilford
Wilford?
掌管这列车的人应该是你 而不是Wilford
You should run the train now, not Wilford.
我不过是因袭前人
I am a shadow of my former shadow.
我的时代早已不在
My day was decades ago.
Gilliam多大了
How old is Gilliam?
闭嘴 Edgar
Shut up, Edgar.
我不是说希望这发生
I'm not saying that I want that to happen,
我不是这个意思
that's not what I'm saying.
我是说他终有一死
What I mean is he will die someday.
当他死后 该是你的继承衣钵
And when that happens, you're gonna have to take over.
你来管理这辆列车
You're gonna have to run the train.
我不是一个领袖
I am not a leader.
我也不清楚
I don't know.
但问我的话我觉得你非常合适
I think you'd be pretty good if you ask me.
Edgar
Edgar.
你还能记起多少过去的事
How far back can you remember?
我也不知道 像什么
I do not know, like what?
你母亲 你还记得她吗
Your mother, you remember her?
我依稀记得一张面容
I can remember a face...
时时浮现
every once in a while.
但不清晰
But it's not clear.
所有人 都躺下
Stay down, everybody.
- 所有人待在原处  - 他妈的看着我
- Everybody stay in your place. - Fucking look at me.
躺下 都躺下
Keep down, keep down.
- 医疗检查 只需要小孩   - 所有小孩和我来
- Medical inspection. Just the kids. - All the kids come with me.
医疗检查而已
It's a medical check up.
就是这样
You're doing good.
所有孩子
Everybody, all the kids.
- 所有孩子  - 你也是  - 没错 到那去
- All the kids? - You too. - That's right, just come.
靠后 女士 请退后
Stay back there, ma'am. Just stay back there.
还有一个
Alright, one more.
快来
Yup, come on.
你得过来
You need to go.
医疗检查而已 你退后
It's just a medical check up. You just stay back there.
好了 和其他人一起
Come on, that's right. Come with the others, okay.
你们 过去检查下
You, go and check.
- 不许动  - 快跑 Timmy
- Don't move. - Go, Timmy!
Timmy
Timmy!
那是她的孩子
That's her baby!
Andy
Andy!
把儿子还给我
Give me back my son.
还给我 你个臭婊子
Give me my son, you fucking bitch!
Andy
Andy!
你们怎么能让他扔鞋子
How could you let him throw his shoe.
- Timmy  - Tim
- Timmy! - Tim!
这种海拔之下 我们只需要7分钟
At this altitude, we need only 7 minutes.
您有7分钟演讲 女士
7 minutes allotted for your speech, sir.
这太令人失望了
This is so disappointing.
不要全翻译 我们只有7分钟
We don't need all that, we only got 7 minutes.
乘客们
Passengers...
这并不是一只鞋
This is not a shoe.
这是目无法纪
This is disorder.
这是10码的骚乱
This is size 10 chaos.
这个 看见了吗 就是死亡
This, you see this? This is death.
在这趟我们称之为家的列车上 有一样东西
In this locomotive we call home, there is one thing...
是它让我们不受冰寒 给我们带来温热
that between our warm hearts and the bitter cold...
衣服 裤子 都不是 是秩序
Clothing? Jeans? No, order.
是秩序将寒冷与死亡隔之门外
Order is the barrier that holds back the cold and death.
我们所有人 列车所有的人都必须
We must all of us, on this train of life...
待在其既定的车厢
remain in our allotted stations...
我们每个人都必须待在
we must each of us occupy...
我们早已安排好的位置上
our preordained particulate positions.
你会把鞋子穿在头上吗
Would you wear a shoe on your head?
你当然不会把鞋穿在头上
Of course you wouldn't wear a shoe on your head.
因为它的位置不在头上
A shoe doesn't belong in your head.
它的位置在脚上
A shoe belongs on your foot.
帽子的位置才在头上
A hat belongs on your head.
而我就是帽子 你们就是鞋
I am a hat, you are a shoe.
我的位置在头上 你们的位置在脚上
I belong on the head, you belong on the foot.
懂了吗 就像这样
Yes? So it is.
最开始 你们买的票就规定了你们所在的位置
In the beginning, order was prescribed by your ticket.
头等厢 经济厢 还有你们这些不请自来的
First bus, economy, and freeloaders like you.
神圣的引擎决定着永恒的秩序
Eternal order is prescribed by the Sacred Engine.
所有东西都来自神圣的引擎
All things flow from the Sacred Engine.
所有事物都有自己的位置
All things in their place.
所有乘客都在已定的位置
All passengers in their sections.
水的流动 热量的上升
All water flowing, all heat rise...
都归功于神圣的引擎
pays homage to the Sacred Engine.
在其早已决定好的
In it's own particulate...
应用的位置上
preordained positions.
就是这样
So it is.
从一开始
Now, as in the beginning...
我就属于车头
I belong to the front.
你们属于车尾
You belong to the tail.
当脚试图取代头的地位
When the foot seeks the place of the head...
他们就打破了神圣的界限
a sacred line is crossed.
知道自己的位置
Know your place.
记住自己的位置
Keep your place.
做好一只鞋
Be a shoe.
我们还剩42秒
We have 42 seconds left.
那我们可以和Wilford先生通一下话
So we can go to comment of Mr. Wilford,
神圣引擎的伟大守护者
the divine keeper of the Sacred Engine.
先生 Wilford先生
Sir? Mr. Wilford?
你在吗
Are you there?
你在吗 先生
Are you there, sir?
通讯断了
It's breaking up. Well...
Wilford先生非常繁忙
Mr. Wilford's a very busy man.
就这样
So it is.
我们就这么坐视不管吗
We're just gonna watch?
- 还不是时候  - 我他妈可不准备在这干坐着
- Not now. - I'm not just gonna fucking sit here.
不用 没事
Nah, alright.
站住 站在那儿 坐下
Stop, stop right there. Sit down.
把那没用的枪放下 快放下
Put that useless gun down. Put it away.
好久不见 Gilliam先生
Long time no see, Mr. Gilliam.
见到你真荣幸
It's a pleasure!
你看起来很健康
You look healthy.
他没事
He's fine.
Mason部长 请帮我带个信给Wilford先生
Minister Mason, please deliver a message to Mr. Wilford.
当然 要我转达什么
Certainly, what should I say?
告诉他我要和他谈一谈
Tell him he and I need to talk.
有什么话跟我说也一样
Well, you can talk to me.
Wilford没理由到这里来
Mr. Wilford has no reason to visit here.
不在这里
Not here.
在车头
At the front.
很好
Nice to hear it.
你的儿子会是个英雄的 我保证
Your son will be a hero, I promise.
或者女儿 随便了
Or daughter, whatever it is.
我来
I got it.
- 你的贡献会被记住的  - 多谢
- Your contribution has been dully noted. - Thanks.
很抱歉在你祈祷的时候打扰你
So sorry to interrupt you while you're praying.
非常抱歉
So sorry.
这是你的佛像 非常感谢
There's your Buddha back, thanks very much.
让开 让开
Move! Move!
别瞎闹了
Stop fooling around.
我有更好的货
I've got a better batch.
更强劲 新鲜 未经切割
Stronger, fresh, uncut.
想来点吗
Want to try some?
多少蛋白块能换10块未切割的柯洛诺
How many protein blocks for 10 rocks of uncut Kronol?
他们没有子弹
They don't have bullets.
你怎么知道的
Why do you say that?
你还记得Mason说的话吗
You remember what Mason said?
她说 把那没用的枪放下
She said, "Put down that useless gun".
她的意思是
She meant...
她不会下令杀了我
she wouldn't give the order to shoot me.
不
No.
我认为那些枪真的没用的
No, I think the guns are literally useless.
他们在4年前的叛乱里用光了所有子弹
They've used up all their bullets 4 years ago on the last revolt.
子弹已经绝迹了
Bullets are extinct.
如果你猜错了 叛乱还没开始我们就会死
If you're wrong, we could be finish before we even start.
我们该更耐心点
I think we should be patient.
等下一张红纸条出现
Wait for the next red letter.
向左
To the left.
再向右
And right.
还不行 抬起来 往左
Not yet, up. Now left.
好了
Good, good.
1 2 1 2 1 2 1 2
1...2...1...2... 1...2...1...2...
在吗 Andrew
Hello? Andrew.
Andrew
Andrew!
醒醒 太阳晒屁股了
Wake-up. Rise and shine.
梦再甜 也不过一枕黄粱而已
When you dream to much of the sun, you forget the trees.
这是你儿子的画像
I believe this is your son.
很抱歉 画得不是很好
I'm sorry, it's not very good.
不是我最好的作品 光线有点暗
It's not my best work, it's a little dark.
但是你要是仔细看他的眼睛
If you look very deep into the eyes,
你能从中看到一丝希望
you can see a little bit of hope.
我的儿子呢 你有画我的小Timmy吗
What about my boy? You got one of Timmy?
当然 Tanya
Yes, Tanya. I do.
别急 别急 别伤着自己
Easy, easy. Don't hurt yourself.
在这呢 给你 你的Timmy
Here, there you go, Timmy.
快看他呀
Look at him.
小脸带着笑
One little smile.
Curtis 你得让我跟你一起
Curtis, you gotta let me come with you.
不行 Tanya 抱歉
No, Tanya, I'm sorry.
你要不让我去就真是对不起我
You will be if you don't let me come.
我会到达车头然后我会
I'm going to the front and I'm
让那个碰我儿子的贱人后悔
gonna make that bitch sorry she put a hand on my boy.
把这个绑紧点
Make this one tighter.
你知道我比那些瘦骨嶙峋的战士们强多了
You know I'm stronger than all these skinny ass soldiers anyway.
求你了
Please.
该死 怎么回事
Shit, what's going on?
计划有变 大家伙全部退后
Change of schedule, boys. Come to back.
抓紧时间
It's now or never.
别慌 按照原定计划
Don't panic. Stick with the plan.
把武器都藏进你们的衣服里
Hide that, hide your weapons in your clothes.
- 清点人数  - 是
- Head check. - Yeah.
站好队
Line up.
坐下
Alright, sit down.
1 2 3 我们现在要怎么办
1...2...3... What the fuck do we do?
6 继续
6...Keep going.
我受够这些狗屁蛋白块了
I've had enough of this protein block bullshit.
没错 太难吃了
Yeah, this is bullshit.
- 我们饿了  - 我们要鸡肉
- I'm hungry. - I want chicken.
我们才不会为这种狗屁东西坐下的
We're not gonna sit down for this shit.
我们要鸡肉 鸡肉
We want chicken! Chicken!
安静 安静
Quiet! Be quiet!
冷静点 没事的
Calm down. It's okay.
你们是想看他死吗 是这样吗
You want him dead? Is that it?
保持安静
Keep quiet.
我们还继续原计划吗
Still going for it, are we?
来吧 我们上
Come on, let's go! Let's do it.
那些步枪
The rifles.
没事的 我们能抢过来
No, we can get them.
我们的人数比他们的子弹要多
We're easily outnumbered their bullets.
就现在
This is it.
Curtis 上吧
Curtis, come on.
就快没时间了 现在必须动手
We're out of time, we gotta do it now.
他们没有子弹 枪里没有子弹
They've got no bullets! They've got no bullets!
继续走 继续
Keep going, keep going!
快把门关上 快关
Close the gate quick. Shut it.
我没事 Grey 快走吧
I'm fine, Grey. You go now.
该死
Fuck.
南宫民秀 柯洛诺毒瘾患者
Nam Koong Min Soo. Kronol addict.
这可真能说明问题
That explains a lot, doesn't it?
- 快点 Edgar  - 怎么个快法
- Hurry up, Edgar. - Hurry up?
让你们都在这干等还真是抱歉
So sorry for keeping you all waiting.
很显然 我尽力了
Obviously I work here so...
- 快打开  - 来了
- Open it. - Here we go.
瘾君子
Kronol head...
这就是柯洛诺 我听说这在头车箱特别抢手
So this is Kronol? I hear it's pretty big in the front section.
小心 就是东西让他们致幻
Careful, that's how these guys hallucinate.
这是工业废料
It's industrial waste.
高度易燃
And it's highly flammable.
你是南宫民秀吗 安全专家
Are you Nam Koong Min Soo, security specialist?
是你设计的
Did you design all the door
所有的门锁和安全系统吗
locks and the security systems on the train?
你看看他 魂不附体的样子 看他的眼睛
Look at him man, he's gone. Look at his eyes.
他脑子已经被那玩意烧坏了
He's fried his brain with that fucking shit.
你是南吗
Are you Nam?
南 能听到吗
Nam, are you listening?
能听到 混蛋
Yes, I'm listening, bastard.
我的名字不是"南"是南宫 蠢货
My name is not "Nem", it is "Nam". Namgoung Minsoo, shit.
南宫是我的名 我姓民秀 混蛋
Namgoung is my name, my surname is Minsoo, asshole.
未知词汇
Unknown words.
请使用正确词汇
Try again with the correct vocabulary.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
帮什么
For what?
我们要到首车厢去
We're going to the front.
我们要你把门打开
And we need you to open up the gates.
如果我不干呢
If I don't want to?
未切割 直接从桶里拿来的
Uncut, straight from the barrel.
你每开一扇门 我给你一块
Every door you open, you get one lap of Kronol.
天啊 万宝路香烟
Jesus, Marlboro Light?
难以置信
I can't believe it.
香烟都消失十几年了
Cigarettes have been extinct for more than 10 years now.
你也想来一口吗 混蛋
You want a smoke too, asshole?
你这样的人渣没资格享用
It's too good for shit like you.
我说白了吧
I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
你帮我们 我们给你毒品
You help us, you get your drug.
不帮的话 我们就把你塞回去
If not, we put you back where we found you.
你怎么选 混蛋
What'll be, asshole?
陈
Chan.
陈 出来 快出来
Chan, get out of here. Let's get out.
够了
That's enough.
我特么要把你塞回抽屉里
I'll put you back in the fucking drawer.
起来
Get up.
我女儿 尤娜 要想往前去 带上她才行
My daughter, Yona. To move forward, we need her.
所以你愿意和我们一起了
So you're coming with us?
每开一扇门 我要两块柯洛诺
For each door, I want two blocks of Kronol.
她也有瘾
She's an addict too?
里面没人
Nobody there.
柯洛诺
Kronol?
看看这些床 人都去哪了
Look at all these beds. Where is everybody?
看上去他们是匆忙离开的
Looks like they left in a hurry.
桌上还有吃的
There's food on the table.
这不会是窗户吧
This can't be a window, can it?
寒冷依旧
Still cold.
一片死寂
Dead.
死气沉沉
All dead.
好了 继续前进
Alright, let's go everyone.
集中注意 我们可不是来看这个的
Stay focus. We didn't come here for this.
听到了 都赶紧动起来 继续走
You heard the man, let's go. Move.
南
Nehm... Nam!
柯洛诺
Kronol!
你怎么知道里面没人的
How did you know there was nobody there?
他跑过来了
He's running.
Paul
Paul?
Paul!
他在干嘛
What is he doing?
他看上去不一样了
He looks so different.
稍等
Just a second.
这东西本来是自动的 但是零件没了也就不好使了
It's used to be automatic, but it's hard when it extinct.
- 这不是我印象中的Paul  - 他不是
- It's not the Paul I remember. - No.
Paul 我是Curtis
Paul? It's Curtis!
他们回不来了 所以现在我只得自己做
They ain't coming back, so now I gotta do it.
人工操作
Manually.
就是这么做的
So that's how it's made.
还是热的
Still hot.
快看
Look at them all.
干得不错
You do some nice work.
没错 这是你们的食物 你们的蛋白块
That's right man, that's your food. That's your protein block.
他们就是因为这个抓你的 来做这些垃圾
Is this why they took you? To make this garbage?
Paul
Paul?
这段时间里你都是一个人吗
You've been alone this whole time?
一个人
Alone.
在这个区
In the zone.
我们要去头车箱 和我们一起吧
We're going to the front. Come with us.
你们要去头车箱 不错
Alright, you're going to the front? Yeah.
但我不去 我的位置就在这儿
But no way, my place is here alright?
在这儿做这种垃圾 为什么
Here? Making this crap? Why?
- 你不能画这个  - 好的
- You can't draw this. - Okay.
哦 天
Oh man.
一直以来 我们吃的就是这种东西
All this time, we've been eating this shit?
我也吃这些
I eat them too, you know?
每天都吃
Every single day.
这个你是从哪拿到的
Where'd you get this?
是你写的这个吗
Have you been the one writing this?
不是我写的
I don't write them...
那你怎么拿到的 谁给你的
Why do you have this? Who gave this to you?
他们就把这个留给我
They just leave them for me.
我把它放进蛋白块里 做上标记
I put them in the protein block, I stamp them on.
就这样
That's it.
供水区
The water supply section?
没错 再过几节车厢就是
Yes, just a few carts up.
那是他们进行水净化和循环的地方
It's where the water's cleansed and recycled.
是整列车最重要的区域之一
It's one of the most crucial sections in the train.
我们占领了那儿 我们就抢占了先机
If we take it, we'll have the upperhand?
甚至都不需要到前车厢去了
We don't even have to go to the very front.
控制了水
We control the water...
就有了谈判的筹码
we control the negotiation.
不好意思打扰下
Excuse me, sorry to bother you there, could I
要是我给你杯水 你能加速点儿吗
get you a glass of water to speed this up?
提高点效率行吧 我们都在干等着你呢
Would you get on with it, man? You're keeping us all waiting.
我的错咯
Is it my fault?
就是你的错
You, you are.
因为你一直都在吸那什么破玩意
Although you've been fucking smelling that thing that...
你可能早就没什么时间概念了
time is a probably a distant concept for you, isn't it?
当然 我就是为柯洛诺才做的
Of course, I do it for the Kronol.
又来了 柯洛诺说个没完
Here we go again. Kronol this, Kronol that...
老天 抓紧干活吧
Christ almighty man, do some work.
是你们要给我那个的
You're the one who's giving me this.
你傻了吗 明明是你
Are you thick? That's what
要求每打开一扇门给你的
you asked for each time you opened the gate.
尤娜 你叫尤娜吧
Yona? It's Yona right?
你多大了
How old are you?
17.
17 那你是出生在火车上的咯
17, you're a train baby then?
你呢
How about you?
17年在陆地上
17 years on earth.
17年在尾车厢
17 years in the tail section.
陆地上
Earth?
那像什么样
What was it like?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
为什么
Why?
遇见Gilliam之前的事我都不想记得
I don't want to remember anything before I met Gilliam.
尤娜
Yona.
你可以透视吗
Are you clairvoyant?
透视 那是什么
Clairvoyant? What's that?
你总是能知道门后发生的事
You always seem to know what's behind the gates.
你是用意念看东西吗
Do you see things in your mind?
别打开
Don't open it.
什么
What?
停下
Stop!
小心点
Be careful.
你也是
You too.
2队 行动
Team 2, move.
向前
Move forward!
火车要通过耶卡特琳娜大桥了
We're passing Yekaterina bridge!
我们上桥了 大伙们
We're at the bridge, guys!
10 9 8 7
10...9...8...7...
5 4 3 2 1
5...4...3...2...1.
新年快乐
Happy new year!
我讨厌变老 真心讨厌
I hate getting old, I hate it.
全体趴下
Everybody down!
坚持住
Hang on.
撞击开始
Impact!
还没完 还有第二下
Not yet. A second one.
都趴下
Stay down.
南 你在干嘛 你要干什么
Nam, what are you doing? What are you doing?
他妈嗑药太多了
He's high as a fucking kite.
就要到了
We're getting closer.
安全通过
Safe passage.
1 2 1 2
One, two. One, two.
新年快乐 你们这些不知道感恩的家伙
Happy Yekaterina bridge, you filthy engraved.
你们 如果不是Wilford大人的庇佑
You people, who if not for the benevolent Wilford...
早在18年前就被冻死了
would have frozen solid 18 years ago today...
你们
You people...
Wilford大人的慷慨之心下你们只会索取
who would suck up the generous titties of Wilford ever since...
食物和庇护
for food and shelter.
现在
And now,
你们却觊觎我们神圣的供水区
in front of our hallowed water supplies section no less...
你们竟然用这无耻暴力
you repay his kindness...
回报他的仁慈之心
with violent hooliganism.
你们这些人渣
You scum.
你们中74%的人今天会死
Precisely 74% of you shall die.
我的朋友 看来你还不明白你们的大限将至
My friend, you suffer from a misplaced optimism of the doom.
这下可精彩的
This is going to be good.
什么 他说什么
What? What did he say?
他说你们死定了
He said you guys are fucked.
你们该把那些士兵打死的
You should beat those sectioners.
耶卡特琳娜大桥之后有一截隧道
There's a tunnel right after Yekaterina...
隧道
A tunnel?
很长的一截
A fucking long one.
还等什么 快跑
What are you doing? Run.
所有人趴下
Everybody down!
上 上 上
Go, go, go!
陈 让开 快让开
Chan, get out, get out.
陈 我们需要火
Chan! We need fire!
陈 把火带来
Chan, bring the fire.
传到后面去 我们需要亮光
Throw them in the back, we're gonna get the lights here.
陈 火把拿来
Chan, the matches.
我要把你们都弄死 狗娘养的东西
We will crush you, motherfuckers!
富余长官
Officer Fuyu!
你在做什么 别看我 去抓他们
What are you doing? Don't look at me. Get them.
放我下来 把抓着我的腿
Put me down, stop squeezing my leg.
投降 投降
Surrender! Surrender!
快投降 不投降 他会杀了我的
Surrender, he'll kill me if we don't surrender.
当然
Sure.
Curtis
Curtis!
住手
Stop!
所有人住手
Stop everybody!
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
住手
Stop!
所有人都住手
Everybody stop!
按他说的做 听到了吗
Do what he says, for crying out loud.
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
别看
Don't look.
活下来的人
Survivors.
把自己洗干净
Wash yourselves.
去供水车厢
The water supplies section...
把血洗干净
Wash away the blood.
你见过这些孩子们吗
Have you seen these kids?
我并不知情
I don't know anything about...
他们在哪 你个臭婊子
Where are they, you bitch?
我不知道 不是我干的
I don't know, it's not me.
告诉我们不然我们就把你的胳膊给砍下来
Tell us or we'll cut your arm you bastard.
Wilford 知道
Wilford knows.
Wilford喜欢小孩子
Wilford likes kids.
真的
He does.
所以他才叫那个黄衣服的女人给他找孩子来
That's why he sent that yellow worm cloth to get them for him.
你们要找的是Wilford 不是我
It's Wilford you want, not me!
Wilford喜欢孩子
Wilford likes kids?
他只在乎他那该死的引擎
All he cares about is his wretched engine.
引擎是神圣的
The engine is sacred.
Wilford也是神圣的
And Wilford is divine.
Wilford是仁慈的
Wilford is merciful.
打给他啊
Call him.
看他会不会来救你
See if he'll come save you.
没错
Yes.
仁慈的Wilford
Wilford the merciful.
打给他啊
Call him.
他不会来这的 他不会离开他的引擎
He won't come here, he won't leave his engine.
就算我们把你撕成碎片 他也不会来吗
We're gonna rip you into little pieces, he still won't come?
等我们控制了并切断了供水 他就会来了
When we control the water and turn that off, he'll have to come.
切断供水
Turn off the water?
你只会害了你们自己人
You'll only be condemning your own people.
水来自前车厢
The water come from the front.
火车前部 它会
The nose of the train, it
破除冰雪然后生成水
breaks up the snow and ice and turns it into water.
就像大象的鼻子
Like an elephant's trunk.
然后送到嘴里
The water comes in the mouth.
不是导入屁股 Curtis
Not in the bum, Curtis.
是的 Wilford对你了解颇深 Curtis Everett先生
Yes, Wilford knows you well, Mr Curtis Everett.
他一直关注着你
He's been watching you.
我们也知道你不是那种置你的人生死于不顾的人
And we know you won't harm your own people.
救不了你的副手
Too bad you couldn't save
真的太遗憾了 他叫什么来着 Edgar吗
your second in command, what was his name? Edgar?
他妈的闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
Curtis先生 我可以帮你
Mr Curtis, I can help you.
你只有死路一条
You can fucking die, is what you can do.
不 我能帮你 我发誓
No, I can help you. I swear it.
听着
Listen to me.
Wilford不会来这里的 他不会来
Wilford won't come here. He's not coming.
你要去找他
You've got to go to him.
而我能带你去
And I can take you.
我对着列车如数家珍 我能保证你的安全
I know the train, I can guarantee you safe passage.
我为什么要信你
Why would I trust you?
因为我想活下去
Because I want to live.
所以你要出卖伟大的Wilford吗
So you'd sell out Wilford the Benevolent?
如果我带你到前面
If I take you to the front...
你得把他杀了
you have to kill him.
我会让你靠近他
I'll get you close enough.
杀了他 放过我
You kill him and let me live.
Curtis
Curtis?
你还是坚持向前吗
You still determined to push ahead?
当然
Of course.
我们还没走到一半呢
We're not even half way.
你已经走的比别人都要远了
You already go further than anyone else.
比四年前的McGregor要远了
Rather than McGregor, 4 years ago.
去不了引擎室的话
10 cars, 20 cars, it doesn't matter
走的多远都没用
unless you make it to the engine.
他们只会再次组织打压我们
They'll just regroup and attack us again.
我们得阻止他们
We gotta pull them up at the routes.
很多人牺牲了
So many have been killed.
我们伤亡惨重
We've lost so many.
我知道
I know.
你看到他们了吗
You seen our men?
他们伤痕累累
They are exhausted.
我叫他们洗干净
I told them to wash themselves...
我好去判断伤势
so I can assess the damage.
让我去吧
Let me go ahead.
我现在有了Mason 我能走的更快
I got Mason now, I can move a lot faster.
你跟伤者留在这里 守着囚犯
You stay here with the wounded and guard the prisoners.
我去夺取引擎室 然后让你做领袖
Let me take the Engine, I'll call for you to lead us.
别这样 Curtis
Stop it, Curtis.
你为什么要这样做
Why are you doing that?
你很清楚你已经是领袖了
You know very well that you're already our leader.
你必须接受这事
You have to accept that.
两臂完好的人怎么当领袖
How can I lead if I have two good arms.
印子淡了
It's faded out.
两臂完整更好
Better to have both arms...
很多事情是一只手做不了的
You can't do a lot with one, you know?
特别是你带着个女人的时候
Especially when you hold a woman.
两臂完整更好 不是吗
Much better to have two arms, won't you agree?
当你到了窄桥
Well you get to the narrow bridge...
那有个写着W的门
big gate with a W on it.
Wilford就在门后面
Wilford's behind that.
别让他讲话
Don't let Wilford talk.
切掉他的舌头
Cut out his tongue.
好了 都来到这里 过来
Okay, let's all get in there. Squeeze in.
很好 很好
Perfect, perfect.
这帽子很适合你
The hat becomes you well.
Grey
Now Grey...
你要跟Curtis走
You must go with Curtis.
漏了一个人
Forgot somebody.
好了
Okay.
柯洛诺
Kronol.
别理我 大家继续工作 继续
Don't mind me, back to work everyone. Back to work.
总理 你没事吗
Minister, are you okay?
没事
I'm okay.
请你不要吃
Please don't eat it...
他们很好的 不咬人
They're very friendly, they won't bite.
可能会咬个番茄
They might bite a tomato.
这也能吃吗
You can eat this too?
列车孩子不会知道这个
A train baby wouldn't know about this.
我踩着它长大
I grew up walking over it.
这埋在雪的下面
This is located under the snow.
在地表上
Of the earth.
这是什么
What is this?
它在动
It moves.
在里面动
Underground.
这是什么意思
What does this mean?
有人想吃寿司吗
Do any of you feel like Sushi?
当然想
Hell yeah...
对吧
Right?
你们真幸运
You people are very lucky.
这一年才开放两次
This is only served twice in a year.
就在一月和七月
In January and July.
为什么 不够鱼吗
Why? Not enough fish?
问题不在数量
Enough is not the criteria.
而是平衡
Balance.
这水族箱是个完整的生态系统
This aquarium is complete ecological system.
每种生物的数量
And the number of individual units...
必须控制的非常的接近
must be very closely, precisely controlled.
才能维持适当的可持续平衡
In order to maintain the proper sustainable balance.
不 你吃这个
No, you eat this.
知道这是什么做的吗
You know what that's made of?
吃吧
Dig in.
Curtis 我的朋友 能不能
Curtis, my friend, do you think that we might...
在下节车厢放开我呢
dispense for the restrain for this next section?
我不是你朋友 我为什么要这样做
I'm not your friend. And why would I?
为孩子着想
For the sake of the young?
教育
Education?
安静
Quiet!
早上好 孩子们
Good morning, children.
很高兴为你们介绍来自尾部的客人
I'm pleased to present guests from tail section.
我们要对尾部客人说什么呢 孩子们
Yes, what do we say to tail section guests, children?
你好 尾部客人
Hello, tail section guests.
Timmy
Timmy!
Andy
Andy!
Andy?
这小男孩
This little boy...
叫做Timmy
His name is Timmy.
是我儿子
This is my son.
请你们好好看下这图片
Please take a good look at the picture.
我看过他们
I saw them.
- 什么时候  - 哪儿
- When? - Where?
从这儿来 往那儿去
Came through there, went through there.
就这些了吗 孩子
Is that all, boy?
对
Yes.
- 他们有哭吗  - 没有 但好像很想哭的样子
- Were they crying? - No, but they looked like they wanted to.
我听说以前尾部的人
I heard Old Tail Sectioners...
都是懒鬼 还吃自己的屎
were lazy dogs and they all drink their own shit.
不 他们都很好
No, they're very nice.
正直仁慈
Very just and merciful.
就是这样
So it is.
Mason总理 我们正要放视频
Minister Mason, we were just about to show a video.
很好
Very good.
Wilford
Wilford!
很小的时候
From a very young age,
Wilford先生就很喜欢火车动力
Mr.Wilford's love of locomotive was apparent.
我长大以后 我要永远住在火车里
When I grow up, I'll live on a train forever.
永远
Forever!
当他的交通帝国
His early dreams were realized...
Wilford工业成立的时候
when he founded his transportation empire...
他的梦想成真了
the Wilford Industries.
等我长大了 我要永远活在火车上
他的梦想成真了
the Wilford Industries.
等我长大了 我要永远活在火车上
但他最大的愿望是
But his greatest dream was to construct...
等我长大了 我要永远活在火车上
但他最大的愿望是
But his greatest dream was to construct...
他的梦想成真了
但他最大的愿望是
But his greatest dream was to construct...
他建立了属于自己的交通帝国
但他最大的愿望是
But his greatest dream was to construct...
工业
但他最大的愿望是
But his greatest dream was to construct...
工业
建立一个豪华机动线路
a luxury locomotive cruiseline...
工业
建立一个豪华机动线路
a luxury locomotive cruiseline...
把整个世界用铁路连接起来
connecting railways of the entire world into one.
万圣节
劳动节
春节
复活节
感恩节
圣诞节
把整个世界用铁路连接起来
connecting railways of the entire world into one.
圣诞节
感恩节
复活节
春节
劳动节
万圣节
一条长达四十三万八千公里的圆形铁路
A circular railway that expands for 438,000 km...
圣诞节
感恩节
复活节
春节
劳动节
万圣节
一条长达四十三万八千公里的圆形铁路
A circular railway that expands for 438,000 km...
一年走一圈
and completes one circle every year.
走过极寒的北极
In the extreme cold of the Arctic,
穿过火烧的非洲沙漠
and the scorching heat of the African desert...
Wildford的火车
Wildford's train is self-sustained...
以精美设计和先进科技
possesses the most sophisticated design...
实现自我维持
advance technology...
难以想象的是
As hard as it is to believe...
旧世界的人取笑Wildford先生
people in the old world made fun of Mr Wildford.
人们指责他对这火车
They criticized him for overengineering...
进行过度设计和过分装备
and overequipping this wonderful train.
但Wildford先生有独特的见解
But Mr Wilford knew something they did not.
什么见解呢
And what was that?
就是全世界那些
All world people are
该死的白痴都会变成冰棍
frigging morons who got turned into popsicles.
大概这样
Sort of.
Wilford知道CW7会冰封这世界
Mr. Wilford knew that CW7 would freeze the world.
那么Wildford先生采取了什么措施
So what did the prophetic Mr Wilford invented?
来保护那少数人逃离灾难呢
To protect the chosen from that calamity?
引擎
The Engine!
轰隆轰隆 咯嗒咯嗒
Rumble rumble, rattle rattle...
永不停止
it will never die!
引擎停了会怎么样
What happens if the engine stops?
我们都会冻死
We'd all freeze and die.
但它会停吗 它会停吗
But will it stop, will it stop?
不 不
No! No!
能告诉我为什么吗
Can you tell us why?
引擎绝不休息 引擎永不停止
The Engine is eternal, the Engine is forever...
轰隆轰隆 咯嗒咯嗒
Rumble rumble, rattle rattle...
这是谁的功劳
who is the reason why?
Wilford
Wilford! Yeah!
Wilford Wilford 好样的
Wilford Wilford, hip hurray!
我喜欢这个 让人振奋
I love that one, such a tonic.
是时候了 孩子们 过来
It's time children, come this way.
小心点
Don't trip now.
别挤 有的是位置
Don't push, there's plenty of room.
谁知道我们要看什么
Who can tell me what's coming up?
那七个人
Those of 7.
注意了 这画面考试会考喔
Pay attention, this tableau will surely on the exam.
十五年前 在列车上的第三年
15 years ago, in the third year of the train...
有七个乘客想要
7 passengers tried to stop...
打破Wilford的奇迹并走了出去
Wilford's miracle train and go outside...
我们的怎么叫这件事的呢 Magdalena
and what do we call this event, Magdalena?
叛走的七子
The Revolt of the Seven.
很好 这事比你们出生还早很多年
Very good, long before you were born.
他们当然不会成功
Of course they failed to stop the train.
最后他们跳出了这列车
Instead they jumped out of the running train.
他们来了
Here they come now.
看 看到没
Look, you see that?
什么
What?
他们在那 那就是他们能支撑的距离
There they are, that's how far they made it.
你之前看过那女人吗
You see that woman before?
她是前车的女仆
She was the maid in the lead car.
因纽特人
An Inuit.
就是爱斯基摩人
An Eskimo, actually.
她很了解冰雪
She knew all about the ice and snow.
她坚信她能在外面生存
She believed she can survive outside.
如果走到外面的话
If we ever go outside the train?
我们都会冻死
We'd all freeze and die.
如果引擎停止的话
If the engine stops running?
我们都会死
We'd all die.
谁在照料神圣的引擎
And who takes care of the Sacred Engine?
Wilford先生
Mr. Wilford.
孩子们 Wilford先生送来了新年蛋
Children, it's the new year eggs from Mr Wilford.
摸摸看 还是暖的
Touch them, they are still warm.
这些蛋是用水煮过的
These eggs are boiled using water...
是神圣的引擎自己加热的
heated by the Sacred Engine itself.
作为特别奖励 为我们弹奏的是
As a special treat, we have playing for us...
世界著名的
the world's renowned first
波士顿交响乐团的首席小提琴手
chair violinist of the Boston Symphony Orchestra,
Gerald Mclnster先生
Mr. Gerald Mclnster.
这真的是Gerald吗
Is that really Gerald?
他看上去很好
He looks damn great.
新年快乐
Happy new year.
谢谢 不用了
No, thank you.
我们走 Curtis
Let's go Curtis.
新年快乐
Happy new year.
我以为母鸡都绝种了
I thought the chickens were extinct.
车上原来还有
There are actually many
那么多传说中已绝种的东西
things on board that were rumored to be extinct.
例如
Such as?
这个
This.
Andrew 别
Andrew! No!
不是我 不是我
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
不
No.
Curtis
Curtis.
你要带领我们
You have to lead us.
Curtis 我的朋友 你了解我的
Curtis, my friend, we understand each other...
听我说 不是我做的
listen to my words, it wasn't me.
我们前进
We go forward.
开门
Open!
快点
Quickly!
是Mason
It's Mason.
操 检查她脉搏
Shit, check her pulse.
喂 别
Hey, don't do...
这情况不妙
That does not look good.
要来了
It happened.
你有主钥匙 对吧
You've got the master key right?
等下 别开枪 请别开枪
Wait, don't shoot. Please don't shoot.
你刚杀了一个前车厢的乘客
You've just killed a front section passenger...
我什么都看不到
I didn't see a thing.
你去哪里 等一下
Where are you going? Wait a minute!
我们能谈一下吗
Could we talk about it just one second?
婊子养的
Son of a bitch!
关门
Close the door.
Tanya
Tanya.
我的Timmy
My Timmy.
My Timmy...
我们会找到他的
We're gonna find him.
我保证
I promise.
我知道
I know.
谢谢
Thank you.
拿着
Take this.
喂 去你妈的 你拿了我的柯洛诺
Come on, motherfucker. You got my Kronol.
我要那东西
I want that shit.
我要我的柯洛诺
I want my Kronol back.
是我的柯洛诺
That's my Kronol.
我发誓 我要杀了你
I swear man, I'm gonna kill you.
开门
Opens the door.
先给我柯洛诺
Kronol first!
你要柯洛诺吗 这里
You want Kronol? Here.
拿着
Take it.
开啊 开门啊
Open it! Open the gate!
你是想要干什么
Are you looking for some trouble or something?
跟这门过不去啊
You got a problem with the gates?
来 抽根烟
Here, smoke a cigarette.
这是你的荣幸
It is a great honor for you.
人类的最后一根烟了
This is the last cigarette of humanity.
好好享受吧
Go enjoy it.
你去过尾部吗
You've ever been to the tail section?
你知道我们上车之后
Do you have any idea what went on back there?
那里是怎样的吗
When we boarded?
一片混乱
It was chaos.
我们没有冻死
We didn't freeze to death.
但我们也没有感激的机会
But we didn't have time to be thankful.
Wilford的士兵拿走了所有东西
Wilford's soldiers came and they took everything.
那铁皮车厢里有上千人
It was thousand people in iron box...
没食物 没水
no food, no water.
一个月后 我们吃了一个瘦个子
After a month, we ate the weak.
你知道我最讨厌自己的什么吗
You know what I hate about myself?
我知道人肉的味道
I know what people taste like.
我知道婴儿的味道最好
I know that babies taste best.
有个女人
There was a woman.
她把孩子藏起来
She was hiding with her baby.
有些拿着刀的人来了
And some men with knives came.
杀了她 抢走了孩子
They killed her and took the baby.
然后来了一个
And then an old man...
没有关系的
no relations, just...
老人
an old man.
他走上前说
He stepped forward and he said...
"把刀给我"
"Give me the knife."
大家都以为他要亲手杀那孩子
Everyone thought he'd killed the baby himself...
但他接过刀
But he took the knife...
砍掉自己的手
and he cut out his own arm...
说"吃这个吧"
and he said, "Eat this".
"你们那么饿的话"
"If you're so hungry..."
"放过孩子 吃这个吧"
"Eat this, just leave the baby".
我从来没看过这样的事
I had never seen anything like that.
那些人放下了刀
And the men put down their knives.
你可能猜到了那老人是谁
You probably guessed who that old man was.
那孩子是Edgar
That baby was Edgar.
而我就是那个拿着刀的人
And I was the man with the knife.
我杀了Edgar的妈妈
I killed Edgar's mother.
然后一个接着一个 其他尾部的人开始
And then one by one, other people in the tail section started...
砍掉手和脚来给他们吃
cutting arms and legs and offering them.
就像是奇迹一样
It was like a miracle.
我也想
I wanted to...
也试过
I tried.
一个月之后 Wilford的人拿来那些蛋白质块
A month later, Wilford's soldiers brought those protein blocks.
我们从此之后就吃那垃圾
We've been eating that shit ever since.
我恨了Wilford十八年了
18 years I hate Wilford.
我等这一刻等了十八年了
18 years I've waited for this moment.
终于来到这了
And now I'm here.
开门
Open the gate.
拜托了
Please.
你的故事很凄美 Curtis
Your story is so beautiful, Curtis.
但我不想开门
But I don't want to open the door.
你知道我想干嘛吗
You know what I want?
我想开一扇门
I want to open a door.
但不是这扇
But not this one.
是那扇
That one.
那扇通往外面的门
The one that leads to the outside.
我们被囚禁了十八年
We've been sentenced for 18 years.
大家都以为那是墙
Everyone thinks it's a wall.
但那他妈的是一扇门
But it's a fucking door.
开了这扇门 我们就能出去了
Open it and get us out of here.
然后冻死吗 你疯了吗
And freeze to death? Are you crazy?
我知道
I know...
但说不定我们能生存呢
But maybe we can survive.
你记得叶卡特琳娜桥吗
You remember Yekaterina bridge?
我们被斧头砍时经过的桥
When we got slaughtered with an ax.
每个新年 我都会去看些东西
Every new year, I check something.
这次我们看到了雪下的
We see the wreckage of a plane...
飞机残骸
under the snow.
十年来 连机尾都看不到
For ten years the tail can barely seen.
我现在却看到了机身的机翼
But now I can see the fuselage and wings.
冰雪已经在减少
There is less and less snow and ice.
在融化了
It melts.
雪花变得脆弱了
Snow becomes more fragile,
要逃离这些并不难
it doesn't take much to get rid of everything.
最近
Recently,
你知道我看到什么了吗
you know what I saw?
我看到外面...
Outside, there was...
算了
Drops.
这不值一提
It is not worth telling it.
你得把柯洛诺给戒了
You gotta take it easy on that Kronol.
那玩意儿会把你脑子烧坏的
That bullshit is gonna fry your brain.
你不信我
You don't think I'm right.
柯洛诺是
Kronol is the first...
最易燃的化学物
highly flammable chemical.
一个火花就会爆炸
A spark and boom!
基本上 那就是个炸弹
Basically, it's a fucking bomb.
我留着不只是想嗨
I not only store these to get high,
还想炸掉这门
but to blow that gate.
火柴 快点
Matches, quickly.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
给我
Give it to me!
炸掉那门
Take that off the door.
火
Fire!
Curtis Everett
Curtis Everett.
我奉Wilford先生的命令来邀请您
I've been asked to extend a formal invitation...
跟他共进晚餐
from Mr. Wilford to join him for dinner.
你先走
After you.
Curtis 是你吗
Curtis? Is that you?
Curtis 好孩子
Curtis, dear boy.
进来
Come in.
让我看看你
Let's take a look at you.
饿了吗
Are you hungry?
你完成了一个男人的使命 一路奋进
You did a man's work, coming all this way.
请坐
Please, sit down.
你是第一个
You are the first human being
走完整个列车的人
to have walked the total length of this train.
从尾部到引擎
Tail to Engine.
你知道吗
Did you know that?
做得好 太赞了
Well done, bravo.
你们没有一个人到过引擎室这里
None of your people have ever been here, to the Engine.
我也没去过尾部
I've never been to the tail section.
为什么 怕脏了您吗
Why not? Too dirty for you?
不想跟臭虫子有身体接触吗
Don't want to rub against the vermin of the tail section?
你以为我的车厢就没缺点吗
Do you think my station is without it's own drawbacks?
很嘈
It's noisy.
还很孤独
And it's lonely.
对
Right.
牛排
Steaks.
地方很大
Plenty of room.
你要什么 这婊子给你拿什么
This whore to bring you anything you want.
Curtis 每个人都有属于他的位置
Curtis, everyone has their preordained position.
而且每个人都处于他自己的位置 就除了你
And everyone is in their place except you.
这就是处于最优的人
That's what people in the best place
对处境最差的人说的话吗
say to the people in the worst place.
这车上没有人
There's not a soul on this
不想跟你交换位置
train that wouldn't trade places with you.
你要跟我交换吗
Would you trade places with me?
操你妈的
Fuck you.
Curtis 好孩子
Curtis, dear boy.
事实上我们都困在这鬼列车里
The fact is that we are all stuck inside this blasted train.
我们都是这铁皮箱里的囚犯
We are prisoners in this hunk of metal.
四分熟行吗
Medium rare?
这列车就是个封闭的生态系统
And this train is a close ecosystem.
我们不停的为了平衡而抗争
We must always strive for balance.
空气 水 食物 人口
Air, water, food supply, population.
都要控制好平衡
It must all be kept in balance.
为了达到最合适的平衡 总要用些
For optimum balance, however there'll have been time when more...
能治本的方法
radical solution would required.
当人口需要减少
When the population needed to be reduced, rather...
大大减少的时候
drastically.
我们没有时间等待物竞天择
We don't have time for true natural selection.
过密的人口与饥饿只会滋生彼此之间的仇恨与罪恶
We would all be hideously over crowded and starved waiting for that.
解决方法只有
The next best solution...
让一群人去杀另一群人
is to have individual units kill off other individual units.
每隔一段时间 我们就要搞一次类似的活动
From time to time, we've had to stir the pot, so to speak.
像是叛变的七子 McGregor Riots事件
The Revolt of Seven, The McGregor Riots...
至于伟大的Curtis起义
The Great Curtis Revolution.
这一轰动事件的结果可是出人意料
A blockbuster production with a devilishly unpredictable plot.
谁能预料到叶卡特琳娜的时候
Who could predicted your
你们会带着火把反击呢
counter attack with the torch at Yaketerina?
很聪明
Pure genius.
那可是Gilliam跟我都预料不到的
That wasn't what Gilliam and I had in our plan.
什么
What?
你该不会不知道吧 Gilliam跟我
Don't tell me you didn't know, Gilliam and I...
我们的计划
Our plan.
Gilliam
Gilliam?
Gilliam.
车头跟车尾合作才能前进
The front and the tail suppose to work together.
他不只是我的搭档 真的
He was more than a partner, really.
他还是我的朋友
He was my friend.
放屁
Bullshit.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我们原本的协议是
Our original agreement was
这起义在叶卡特琳娜隧道结束
for the insurgency to end at Yaketerina tunnel.
存活下来的人就回到尾部
And all the survivors will go back to the tail section...
- 享受比原来更大的空间  - 你说谎
- To enjoy a much more space. - You're a fucking liar.
Gilliam不会这样做的
Gilliam would never do that.
这计划屡试不爽
It all worked out in the end.
而你们的反击
Your counter attack actually
让这次起义变得刺激多了
made the insurgency 10 times more exciting.
不幸的是
Unfortunately the front
前车遭受的损失也严重多了
suffered more losses than anticipated and...
Gilliam要付出代价
Gilliam had to pay the price.
很讽刺 不是吗
Ironic, isn't it?
生与死
How people dramatically cross
只是一线之差
that thin barrier between life and death...
现在就剩下最后一步了
now there's just one last thing for us to do.
点算人数
Tally up the numbers.
你好 Wilford 是我
Hello Wilford, it's me.
我在Gilliam这里
I'm at Gilliam's place.
等下
Hold on.
人数没再变了吗
Is it still the same number?
对 还是百分之七十四
Yes, it still stands at 74%.
好的 继续
Okay, carry on.
等等
Wait.
留下十八个 庆祝十八周年
Spare 18, to celebrate our 18th year.
这主意太好了
It's an excellent idea.
都是你的人
Your people.
他妈的 Claude 小心引擎
Goddammit Claude. Mind the Engine!
她最近很敏感
She's getting sensitive recently.
坐下 有点礼貌
Sit down and mind your table manners.
别紧张
Relax.
冷静点
Calm down.
现在我明白Gilliam的意思了
Now I can see what Gilliam meant,
他说你很厉害很聪明
he told me you were brilliant and clever.
就是神经太紧张
But always so tense.
你上次做爱是什么时候了
When's the last time you got laid?
像Gilliam说的 抱着个女人最好有两只手
Like Gilliam said, holding a woman is much better with two arms.
我会怀念他的
I'll miss Gilliam.
我会怀念那些深夜里的电话聊天
I'll miss our late night phone chats.
他可以说好几个小时
He could go on for hours.
只用一只手而已
All with only one arm.
那脸是怎么回事
What's with that face?
你是怎么了
What's the matter?
你看着像疯子一样
You look like a crazy person.
这车上疯子已经够多了
As if there aren't enough crazies on this train.
血
Blood!
你没事吗
Are you okay?
什么 发生什么事
What? What happened?
趴下
Get down.
尤娜
Yona.
我们要开这个门
We must open this door.
看到那些线了吗
You see those cables?
这太多线了
There are so many cables.
死
Die!
混蛋
Bastard!
在这列车上 只有疯子
It is easier for someone to survive on this train...
才能更好的活着
if they have some level of insanity.
Gilliam很明白
As Gilliam well understood...
我们要维持紧张 惊慌
we need to maintain the proper balance of anxiety and fear...
混乱和恐惧的平衡才能活着
chaos and horror in order to keep life going.
如果没有这些的话 我们就要自己创造
If we don't have that, we need to invent it.
这方面 你带领的Curtis起义
In that sense, the Great Curtis revolution
可就是大师级的作品了
you invented was truly a masterpiece.
尤娜
Yona.
红色 八号线
Red, number 8.
七号
No, 7.
跟我来 Curtis
Come with me, Curtis.
我想给你看些东西
Something I want to show you.
你应得的
You deserve it.
来吧
Come on.
她在苏醒了
She's waking up now.
很舒适 对吧
Cozy yes?
平和
Peaceful.
现在你在她的心脏里
You are now in her heart.
我为这奉献了一生
I've devoted my entire life for this.
永动引擎
The Eternal Engine.
它自己运作 永不停止
It is the eternity itself.
你试过在这车上独处吗
Have you ever been alone on this train?
上一次你独处是什么时候了
When was the last time you were alone?
记不起来了 不是吗
You can't remember, can you?
那么请你
So please do.
慢慢享受
Take your time.
我刚写的
I just wrote it.
为你写的 Curtis
It's for you, Curtis.
来
Here.
我老了
I am old.
我希望你接替我的位置
I want you to take my Station.
这是你一直梦想的事
It's what you've always wanted.
也是Gilliam梦想的事
It's what Gilliam wanted too.
你要照料这引擎
You must tend the Engine...
让她保持运转
Keep her humming.
听着 Curtis
Look, Curtis.
这门后面
Beyond the gate...
一个车厢接着一个车厢
Sections after sections precisely where they've
永远的在那里谨守岗位
always been and where they'll always be.
它们连起来成了什么
All adding up to what?
这列车
The train.
现在这完美的人口 大家都
And now the perfectly correct number of human beings...
处于自己的位置 这加起来是什么
All in their proper places, all adding up to what?
是全人类
Humanity.
这列车就是世界
The train is the world.
我们就是全人类
We the humanity.
现在你有着带领全人类的神圣职责
And now you have the sacred responsibility to lead all humanity.
没有你的话 Curtis 人类会绝种的
Without you, Curtis, humanity will cease to exist.
你看过人们没有领袖的样子
You've seen what people do without leadership.
他们会吞噬其他人
They devour one another.
尤娜 柯洛诺
Yona, the Kronol!
尤娜 停 别
Yona, stop! No.
没子弹了吗
No bullets?
去拿柯洛诺
Get the Kronol then.
看看他们
Look at them.
这就是他们的样子
That's how people are.
你知道的
You know.
你看过的
You've seen this.
你经历过的
You've been this.
可笑又可悲 不是吗
Ridiculous. Pathetic, aren't they?
你能拯救他们
You can save them from themselves.
Gilliam拯救你就是为了这个
This is what Gilliam saved you for.
Curtis
Curtis.
这是你的命运
This is your destiny.
好了
It's done!
Curtis 火柴
Curtis, matches.
Curtis! The match!
这地方只能容纳很小的人
The space only allows for a very small person.
五岁以下的小孩
Young children under 5.
虽然引擎是永动的 但不表示所有部件都不用替换
The engine lasts forever but not to all of it's parts.
最近那零件绝种了
That piece of equipment went extinct recently.
我们得找代替品
We needed a replacement.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness
尾部为我们源源不断的提供小孩
the tail section manufactured us a steady supplies of kids.
好让这能人力维持
So we can keep going manually.
操你妈的混蛋
Fucking bastard!
尤娜
Yona...
拿着火柴
Take the fire.
只剩一个了
Only one left.
总引擎关闭
Critical engine shutdown.
好了
Okay.
请保持安全距离
Please stand at safe distance.
Andy 是你吗
Andy? Is that you?
Andy
Andy!
你记得我吗
Do you remember me?
Andy 停下 听我说
Andy, stop, listen to me.
别走上去 听着
Don't go up those stairs, listen.
Andy
Andy!
过来 过来这里
Come here, come over here.
Andy 听我说
Andy, listen to me!
离开那里
Get out of there!
妈的 Andy 听我说
Goddammit Andy, listen to me.
Curtis 别那么狗血好吗
Curtis, don't be so melodramatic.
你知道每个人都有属于他的位置的
You know everyone has their own preordained position.
很好
Nice.
爸爸
Dad!
Dad...
Curtis
Curtis.
留在这
Stay here.